# Olin Kirkland

Brühler Landstraße 2, 50997 Köln, Germany plakat@live.com; +49 162 372 0898

https://www.olinkirk.land

# **SUMMARY**

I am an adaptable programmer and UI developer with a passion for making games, producing high quality OOP code, and creating user interfaces. My professional experience includes core front-end development for large scale applications, game development, and game design. In my free time, I work on personal game-related projects with an emphasis on procedural generation.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: ActionScript 3.0, Apache Flex, Javascript, C#
- IDEs: IntelliJ IDEA, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, FlashDevelop, Flash Builder
- Adobe Suite: Adobe Animate, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- Version Control: Git
- Communication: Native speaker of English and German

#### **EDUCATION**

## George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, United States

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2011 – June 2013

## Oakton High School, Fairfax, VA, United States

Graduated with Advanced Placement September 2007 – June 2011

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

References to Adobe Air/Adobe Flash imply the language Actionscript 3.0

# BRIGHT FUTURE, Cologne, NRW, Germany

Game Developer (Full time), April 2020 – Present

- Work closely with other programmers and designers to develop and maintain a massively-multiplayer browser game
- Debug and refactored the game's codebase with an emphasis on improving performance
- Work collaboratively using version control (Perforce and Git)
- Technologies: Haxe, OpenFl

# DALLMEIER, Regensburg, BY, Germany

Flex Developer (Full time), May 2018 – April 2020

- Worked closely with other programmers and designers to build intuitive user interfaces
- Developed various interactive modules for displaying and visualizing data
- Worked collaboratively using version control (Git)
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Apache Flex, RESTful Web API

## HOUSTON MUSEUM OF NATURAL SCIENCE, Houston, TX, United States

Contract Interactive Developer (Freelance), September 2017 – May 2018

- Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science, one of the most popular museums in the United States
- Worked closely with curators to build content-rich exhibits to inform and entertain visitors
- Organized and led meetings with museum docents and volunteers
- Constructed and maintained a custom database for researchers
- Designed and developed a cutting edge interactive kiosk using LEAP Motion technology
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flash, Apache Flex, C#, LEAP Motion

# PAUL BERNHARD EXHIBIT DESIGN AND CONSULTING, Houston, TX, United States

Interactive Developer, September 2015 – May 2018

- Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science
- Directed the organization and implementation of museum content for custom applications
- Wrote code to interface with custom hardware (sensors like the LEAP Motion and Arduinos)
- Produced maps based on custom data sets using industry standard GIS tools
- Programmed visualizations for data from a wide variety of formats and sources including data from RESTful APIs related to the energy sector and extensive industry data sets
- Communicated with engineers, graphic designers, and researchers during development
- Created concepts and layouts as detailed storyboards for graphic designers to build on
- Managed and carried out the deployment of applications to their intended hardware
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flex, C#, Unity, HTML, Javascript, Adobe Flash, Arduino

#### **ZENITH LEARNING, Houston, TX, United States**

Teacher (Part time), January 2017 – June 2017

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting (after school activities for students)

#### RENAISSANCE CHILD, Arlington, VA, United States

Camp Instructor (Full time), April 2015 – September 2015

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering, stop-motion, programming, and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

## ODESK.COM

Interactive Media Developer and Graphic Designer (Freelance), June 2013 – April 2015

- Conferred with clients to discuss and determine layout design, and functionality of software
- Developed and implemented graphics and layouts for company applications
- Reviewed final layouts and suggested improvements as needed
- Maintained an organized archive of versions and products

## GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY, Fairfax, VA, United States

Flash Developer (Part time), January 2012 – May 2013

- Created concepts and sample layouts to run by management
- Developed interactive web applications to allow users to explore university floor plans and virtual tours
- Performed tests of web applications to be sure they produced the desired results
- Technologies: Adobe Flash